ALBERTO GAONA

Coahuila, México

albertoo_3c@hotmail.com

+52 844-278-3346

GitHub

LinkedIn

Portfolio

Engineering graduate offering one year of experience in building artificial neural networks used for computer vision, natural language processing, and voice user interfaces. Seeking to replicate, harness, and publish cutting-edge deep learning papers into an artificial intelligence research engineer position.

SKILLS

Proficient: Python, C++, PyTorch, OpenCV, Matplotlib, Numpy, Git, Latex.

Moderate: TensorFlow, Keras, Java, C#, SQL, Pandas, AWS-EC2 instances, Linux.

PROJECTS

Automatic Hair Segmentation

Source code - 10/2018

- Outperformed the part labels dataset which contains labelings of +2500 face images into hair, skin, and background labels by implementing a U-Net architecture using Keras that generates more precise labels.
- Improved the hair segmentation exactness by post-processing the model prediction output with a fully connected CRF and an image matting algorithm using Python

Dermatologist Al

Source code - 10/2018

• Built a deep learning model that distinguish malignant melanoma from two benign skin lesions, nevus, and keratosis, with 79% confidence by adapting a pre-trained Inception v3 model using PyTorch.

Real-time Facial Landmarks Recognizer

Source code - 01/2018

- Built an optimized convolutional neural network using Keras that identifies the location of 15 facial key-points with just 0.0015 of loss.
- Combined the OpenCV framework with the previous CNN model to create a recognition system that takes in an image or live stream containing faces and successfully determines the location of each face and their 15 facial key-points.

EDUCATION

Udacity On line

Artificial Intelligence and Specializations Nanodegree Deep Learning Nanodegree Foundation

09/2017 - 03/2018 03/2017 - 08/2017

Digital Invaders

Saltillo, Coahuila

Innovation and Technological Creativity

08/2016 – 12/2016

Autonomous University of Coahuila

Arteaga, Coahuila

Computer Systems Engineer Bachelor's Degree

08/2012 - 06/2017

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Autonomous University of Coahuila

Saltillo, Coahuila

Software Engineer Intern

03/2017 - 07/2017

• Streamline more than 57% the time it takes for each of the 32,000+ university's students to perform administrative procedures by coding a multi-platform mobile application prototype that allows to do them wherever they are.

01/2015 - 06/2015

- Used the available documentation to re-engineering and upgrade the intranet for the university's alumni program.
- Reduced approximately 60% of the registration process to the alumni program by developing an Android app that streamlines the complementary administrative procedures benefiting 43 higher education institutions.